<!--
  ~ Copyright 2011-2013 Kay Stenschke
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->

<idea-plugin version="2">
    <name>Shifter</name>
    <description><![CDATA[
    Detects type of keyword at caret and shifts it "up" or "down" on keyboard shortcut.
    If there's only one shiftable word in a line, it can be shifted without the caret touching it.
    Lowercase/uppercase or lower case with upper first character of shifted words is maintained.<br/>
    <br/>
    Supported generic shifting types:
    <ul>
        <li>Shifting a multi-line selection sorts the lines alphabetically ascending/descending.</li>
        <li>Shifting a single-line selection, that is a comma separated list, sorts the items ascending/descending.</li>
        <li>Shifting a selection within a single line (that is not CSV), detects and swaps characters: single quote vs. double quote OR slash vs. backslash</li>
        <li>Numeric values - Increments/decrements numbers by 1</li>
        <li>UNIX timestamps - Increments/decrements by one day, shows a balloon info with the shifted date in human-readable format</li>
        <li>PHP variables - Shifts to alphabetically next/previous variable name found in current document</li>
        <li>Strings wrapped in single/double quotes and backticks - Shifts to alphabetically next/previous quoted string found in current document</li>
        <li>CSS hex RGB colors - Shifts color value lighter/darker</li>
        <li>CSS length values - Shifts numeric length values up/down by 1 (units: em, in, px, pt, cm)</li>
        <li>Encoding/decoding of HTML special characters</li>
        <li>Single characters and string consisting from any amount of the same character can be shifted to the prev/next ASCII value</li>
        <li>Strings ending with numbers - increments/decrements the postfix</li>
    </ul>
    Dictionaric keyword shifting: Shifter comes with a customizable, file extension specific and globally useable dictionary of shiftable keywords.
    Some keyword types from the default dictionary:<br/>
    <ul>
        <li>PHP core magical constants - Shifts PHP's magic constants (__FILE__/__LINE__ etc.)</li>
        <li>CSS orientations and positioning: top/right/bottom/left and absolute/relative, and geographical directions (north/east/south/west)</li>
        <li>Accessibility types: public/private/protected</li>
        <li>MySql data types: Shifts to next bigger/smaller numeric/string type</li>
        <li>Primitive data types of Java, JavaScript, PHP, Objective-C</li>
        <li>Doc comment tags (Java, JavaScript, PHP)</li>
        <li>JavaScript event types (mouse, keyboard, frame/object, forml, control, touch)</li>
        <li>Named colors from the sRGB color space (white/lightgray/gray...)</li>
        <li>Text styles (bold, italic...)</li>
        <li>Web image (gif/jpg/png) and audio (au/aif/wav etc.) format extensions</li>
        <li>Full and abbreviated names of months and weekdays and units of time</li>
        <li>Logical operators (and/or/xor/not), arithmetic operations (addition/subtraction...) and arithmetic elements (sum/difference/product..)</li>
        <li>Metasyntax terms: foo/bar/baz...</li>
        <li>Names of common data collection types (list/set/bag/dictionary/tree...)</li>
        <li>Names of numbers (one/two/three etc.) and ordinal numbers (first/second/third  etc.)
        <li>Boolean (paired) keyword values - Toggles true/false, on/off, yes/no (e.g. Objective-C), shown/hidden, show/hide, positive/negative, from/until, enable(d)/disable(d), pass/fail, min/max, expand/collapse, asc/desc, first/last
        </li>
    </ul>
    <br/>Default keyboard shortcuts:
    <ul>
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+Comma  - Shift Down
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+Period - Shift Up
    </ul>
    <br/>Please note: This plugin is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ]]></description>
    <vendor url="" email="info@stenschke.com">Kay Stenschke</vendor>
    <version>1.1.6</version>
    <idea-version since-build="8000"/>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    1.1.6<br/><ul><li>Improved compatibility: Compiled with JDK target bytecode version 1.6 (was 1.7)</li></ul>
    1.1.5<br/><ul><li>Added sorting mode to settings: case sensitive/in-sensitive</li></ul>
    1.1.4<br/><ul><li>Added shifting of numeric postfixes of strings</li></ul>
    1.1.3<br/><ul><li>Made sorting of lines and lists case insensitive</li></ul>
    1.1.2<br/><ul>
        <li>Added support for shifting negative numeric- and CSS pixel values</li>
        <li>Added support for shifting more CSS length types: em, pt, cm, in</li>
    </ul>
    1.1.1<br/><ul><li>Added HTML special chars encoding/decoding</li></ul>
    1.1.0<br/><ul><li>Made shifter dictionary customizable via plugin configuration</li></ul>
    1.0.12<br/><ul><li>Added character swapping inside single-line selection: single vs. double quote OR slash vs. backslash</li></ul>
    1.0.11<br/><ul>
        <li>Added shifting of words consisting from any amount of the same character to the next ASCII character</li>
        <li>Added shifting of web image and audio format file extensions</li>
        <li>Added shifting of names of english ordinal numbers and numbers</li>
        <li>Added shifting of DOM touch and control events</li>
        <li>Added shifting of text styles</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.10<br/><ul>
        <li>Bugfix: shifting line with regex meta characters possibly caused exception</li>
        <li>Changed menu items labels and order, disable items when no editor available</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.9<br/><ul>
        <li>Added shifting of meta-syntax terms</li>
        <li>Added shifting of logical operators, arithmetical operations and elements</li>
        <li>Added shifting of geographical orientations and time units</li>
        <li>Added shifting of data collection type names</li>
        <li>Extended shiftable "boolean" keyword pairs</li>
        <li>Bugfix: shifting with caret at EOF failed</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.8<br/><ul>
        <li>Added shifting of strings wrapped in backticks</li>
        <li>Added shifting of PHP core magical constants (__FILE__, __LINE__, etc.)</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.7<br/><ul>
        <li>Added balloon info with human-readable date when shifting UNIX timestamps</li>
        <li>Added shifting of UNIX timestamps +/- one day</li>
        <li>Added shifting of named colors from the sRGB color space (white, lightGray, gray...)</li>
        <li>Added shifting of abbreviated month and weekday names (jan, feb, ... and mon, tue, ...)</li>
        <li>Added shifting of JavaScript event types (mouse, keyboard, frame/object, form)</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.6<br/><ul>
        <li>Improved shiftable word types detection</li>
        <li>Added Objective-C specific data types</li>
        <li>Bugfix: Shifted quoted strings were partly maintaining wrong case</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.5<br/><ul>
        <li>Added auto-completion of shifted JsDoc method tag with respective function name</li>
        <li>Added shifting of data types inside Java, JavaScript and PHP doc comments</li>
        <li>Added maintaining of lower case with upper first character</li>
        <li>Added option to sort items of selected comma separated list</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.4<br/><ul>
        <li>Added support for single/double quoted strings: shifts to aphabetically next/previous quoted string in current file</li>
        <li>Added shifting of CSS positioning: absolute/relative</li>
        <li>Added shifting of Objective-c booleans YES/NO</li>
        <li>Bugfix: PHP variables containing underscores were not detected</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.3<br/><ul>
        <li>Added support for PHP variables: shifts to alphabetically next/previous variable in current file</li>
        <li>Added shifting of numeric values w/o units</li>
        <li>Added ability to undo/redo shifter actions</li>
        <li>Changed CSS pixel values shifting size to 1</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.2<br/><ul>
        <li>Added alphabetical ascending/descending sorting of multi-line selections.</li>
        <li>Added shifting of doc-params @param/@return</li>
        <li>Added shifting of months, weekdays and CSS orientations: top/right/bottom/left</li>
        <li>Added shifting of a whole line: a single shiftable word in the edited line is detected</li>
        <li>Added maintaining of uppercase/lowercase for all types</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.1<br/><ul>
        <li>Added shifting of MySql data type keywords</li>
        <li>Added CSS pixel value shifting</li>
        <li>Added accessibility keywords shifting</li>
        <li>Added conversion of triple digit CSS RGB values to six digits</li>
        <li>Added case sensitivity for booleans</li>
    </ul>
    1.0.0<br/><ul><li>Initial release</li></ul>
  ]]></change-notes>

    <application-components>
    </application-components>

    <project-components>
        <component>
            <implementation-class>com.kstenschke.shifter.ShifterSettingsComponent</implementation-class>
            <loadForDefaultProject/>
        </component>
    </project-components>

    <actions>
        <group id="ShifterActionGroup" text="Shift Word at Caret / Line / Selection" popup="false">
            <separator/>

            <action id="ShiftUpAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftUpAction" text="Shift-Up"
                    description="Shift-Up Word at Caret / Line / Selection">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt PERIOD"/>
            </action>
            <action id="ShiftDownAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftDownAction" text="Shift-Down"
                    description="Shift-Down Word at Caret / Line / Selection">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt COMMA"/>
            </action>

            <add-to-group group-id="EditMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </group>
    </actions>


    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">

    </extensions>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.lang</depends>
</idea-plugin>