<!--
  ~ Copyright 2011-2017 Kay Stenschke
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<!DOCTYPE idea-plugin PUBLIC "Plugin/DTD" "http://plugins.intellij.net/plugin.dtd">
<idea-plugin url="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/idea/plugin/6149">
    <id>Shifter</id>
    <name>Shifter</name>
    <version>1.7.1</version>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/kstenschke/shifter-plugin" email="info@stenschke.com">Kay Stenschke</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    Detects type of selection, line or keyword at caret and shifts it "up" or "down" on keyboard shortcut.
    If there's only one shiftable word in a line, it can be shifted without the caret touching it.
    Lowercase/uppercase or lower case with upper first character of shifted words is maintained.<br/>
    <br/>
    <strong>DEFAULT KEYBOARD SHORTCUTS</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+Comma  - Shift Down</li>
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+Period - Shift Up</li>
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+K - Shift Up More*</li>
        <li>Ctrl+Shift+Alt+J - Shift Down More*</li>
    </ul>
    <br/>
    Shift more: repeats shifting the selected value multiple times. The amount of repetitions can be configured in the plugin configuration (default: 10).
    <br/><br/>
    <strong>SHIFTING TYPES</strong>
    <br/>
    <strong>Sorting</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>Shifting a multi-line selection sorts the lines alphabetically ascending/descending.</li>
        <li>Shifting a single-line selection, that is a comma- or pipe-separated list, sorts the items ascending/descending.</li>
        <li>Shifting a single-line selection, that is a tupel, flips the items' order (delimiters: ":", "|", ", ", " - ", " + ", " < ", " > ", " <= ", " >= ", " == ", " != ", " === ", " !== ", " || ")</li>
        <li>Shifting a selection that is a camelCased (w/ lower or upper lead character) word pair, flips the order of the words.</li>
        <li>Shifting a selected (from questionmark on) ternary expression, swaps "than" and "else" statements</li>
        <li>Shifting a selected PHP concatenation from two strings / variables, toggles the concatenated items' order</li>
        <li>Shifting a selection from a CSS file, sorts all attributes inside their selectors (alphabetically, vendor-attributes and vendor-styles at the end)</li>
        <li>Shifting selected attribute-style lines inside a CSS (or LESS or SASS) file, sorts them (alphabetically, vendor-attributes and vendor-styles at the end)</li>
    </ul>
    <strong>Numeric Shifting</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>Numeric values - Incrementing/decrementing numbers</li>
        <li>Strings ending with numbers - increments/decrements the postfix</li>
        <li>Numeric block selection: opens dialog to chose: 1. in/decrement each or: 2. replace by enumeration</li>
        <li>UNIX (and millisecond based) timestamps - Increments/decrements by one day, shows a balloon info with the shifted date in human-readable format</li>
        <li>CSS hex RGB colors - Shifts color value lighter/darker</li>
        <li>CSS length values - Shifts numeric length values up/down by 1 (units: em, in, px, pt, cm, rem, vw, vh, vmin, vmax)</li>
        <li>Increment/decrement roman numerals</li>
    </ul>
    <strong>String Manipulations</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>Shifting a selection within a single line: detects and swaps characters: single quote vs. double quote OR slash vs. backslash</li>
        <li>Shifting a selected (or the caret touching a) camel-cased string, converts it into a minus-separated path (and vice versa)</li>
        <li>Strings wrapped in single/double quotes and backticks - Shifts to alphabetically next/previous quoted string found in current document</li>
        <li>Logical operators: toggles between (selected) "&&" and "||"</li>
        <li>HTML en/decoding of selected special characters</li>
        <li>Single characters and string consisting from any amount of the same character can be shifted to the previous/next ASCII value</li>
    </ul>
    <strong>Code- and DOC Comments</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>Selection which is a block comment or multiple line-comments (e.g. PHP, JavaScript, C syntax) - toggle among comment type (//... vs. /*...*/). Merges multi-line comments into 1 line.</li>
        <li>Selected line of code ending with a trailing //-comment - Moves the comment into a new line before the code</li>
        <li>Selected HTML comment inside a PHP / PHTML file: converts it into a PHP block comment (and vice versa)</li>
        <li>PHP DOC: Shifting a selected PHP doc comment block that contains @param comments w/ variable name but no data type, guesses and inserts data types</li>
        <li>PHP DOC: Shifting while the caret is inside an @param line that contains no data type, inserts a data type (guessed from the variable name)</li>
        <li>JsDOC: Shifting w/ the caret touching a data type that is not wrapped in curly brackets, inside an @param- adds the missing curly brackets</li>
        <li>Selected JsDoc block: Convert "@return" into "@returns", add curly brackets around data types in "@param" and "@returns" lines, correct invalid data types into existing primitive data types (event => Object, int(eger) => number), guess and insert missing data type to "@param" and "@returns" lines, reduce empty JsDoc lines</li>
    </ul>
    <strong>PHP and JavaScript</strong>
    <ul>
        <li>PHP variables - Shifts to alphabetically next/previous variable found in current document ("shift more" shifts until first variable with a different first letter)</li>
        <li>Selected PHP array - Shifts among long and shorthand syntax (PHP >= 5.4)</li>
        <li>Selection which is a Sizzle-Selector - Converts the selector into a corresponding JavaScript variable declaration</li>
        <li>Selection of multiple JavaScript var declarations in succession - are joined into multiple comma-separated declarations</li>
    </ul>
    <strong>Dictionaric Keyword Shifting</strong>
    <br/>
    Shifter comes with a customizable, file extension specific and globally usable dictionary of shiftable keywords.
    Some keyword types from the default dictionary:<br/>
    <ul>
        <li>PHP core magical constants - Shifts PHP's magic constants (__FILE__/__LINE__ etc.)</li>
        <li>CSS orientations and positioning: top/right/bottom/left and absolute/relative, and geographical directions (north/east/south/west)</li>
        <li>Accessibility types: public/private/protected</li>
        <li>MySql data types: Shifts to next bigger/smaller numeric/string type</li>
        <li>Primitive data types of Java, JavaScript, PHP, Objective-C</li>
        <li>Doc comment tags (Java, JavaScript, PHP)</li>
        <li>JavaScript event types (mouse, keyboard, frame/object, form, control, touch)</li>
        <li>Named colors from the sRGB color space (white/lightgray/gray...)</li>
        <li>Text styles (bold, italic...)</li>
        <li>Web image (gif/jpg/png) and audio (au/aif/wav etc.) format extensions</li>
        <li>Full and abbreviated names of months and weekdays and units of time</li>
        <li>Logical operators (and/or/xor/not), arithmetic operations (addition/subtraction...) and arithmetic elements (sum/difference/product..)</li>
        <li>Meta-syntax terms: foo/bar/baz...</li>
        <li>Names of common data collection types (list/set/bag/dictionary/tree...)</li>
        <li>Names of numbers (one/two/three etc.) and ordinal numbers (first/second/third  etc.)
        <li>Boolean (paired) keyword values - Toggles true/false, on/off, yes/no (e.g. Objective-C), shown/hidden, show/hide, positive/negative, from/until, enable(d)/disable(d), pass/fail, min/max, expand/collapse, asc/desc, first/last
        </li>
    </ul>
    <br/>Please note: This plugin is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <ul>
        <li>1.7.1
            <ul>
                <li>Improved: PHP DOC @param data type insertion - can now also be invoked from selected line out of DOC comment block</li>
            </ul>
        </li><li>1.7.0
            <ul>
                <li>Added: Shifting a selected (or the caret touching a) camel-cased string, converts it into a minus-separated path (and vice versa)</li>
                <li>Added: Shifting a camel-cased string, consisting from only 2 words, shows an intention popup to either swap the words' order or convert to a minus-separated path</li>
                <li>Added: Sort all attributes of selected selectors in a CSS stylesheet selection (alphabetically, vendor-attributes and vendor-styles at the end)</li>
                <li>Added: Sort selected attribute-style lines in a CSS stylesheet (alphabetically, vendor-attributes and vendor-styles at the end)</li>
                <li>Added: Sorting CSS attribute-style lines detects and adds a missing semicolon on the last line, before sorting</li>
                <li>Added: Intention popup when selection is both: sortable multi-line, containing swappable quotes</li>
                <li>Improved: Shifting of single-lined PHP DOC block comments</li>
                <li>Improved: Shifting of c-style line comments</li>
                <li>Improved: Better case maintaining during dictionaric word shifting</li>
                <li>Improved: Sorting selected lines was possible only from 3+ lines</li>
                <li>Improved: More PHP DOC and JsDoc data type detections from argument names</li>
                <li>Improved: Natural sort (added case insensitivity)</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li>1.6.1 Improved: Better JsDoc comment block detection</li>
        <li>1.6.0
            <ul>
                <li>Added: Correct selected invalid JsDoc block comment - convert "@return" into "@returns", add curly brackets around data types in "@param" and "@returns" lines, correct invalid data types into existing primitive data types (bool => boolean, event => Object, int(eger) => number),  guess and insert missing data type into "@param" and "@returns" lines, reduce empty JsDoc lines</li>
                <li>Added: Shift invalid JsDoc "@return" statement at caret into "@returns"</li>
                <li>Shifted DOC block comment in PHP and JavaScript: reformat DOC block after correction</li>
                <li>Added: Timestamp shifting unit (seconds or milliseconds) can be specified per file type in plugin settings</li>
                <li>Improved: Better case maintaining of shifted words</li>
                <li>Changed: Grouped shifting types in features list for easier comprehensibility</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li>1.5.5
            <ul>
                <li>Added: Add missing curly brackets around data type at caret in jsDoc @param line</li>
                <li>Added: Mode selection popup when selection is both: sortable list, swappable quote signs</li>
                <li>Added: Mode selection popup when selection is both: PHP concatenation (order can be toggled), swappable quote signs</li>
                <li>Improved: Sorting a selection of lines w/ common delimiter no longer removes leading whitespace</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
  </ul><br/>
   <a href="https://github.com/kstenschke/shifter-plugin/blob/master/CHANGELOG.textile" style="color:#6cb1f5" target="_blank">...Read full changelog on github</a>
  ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- see http://www.jetbrains.org/intellij/sdk/docs/basics/getting_started/build_number_ranges.html -->
    <idea-version since-build="8000"/>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.lang</depends>

    <application-components>
    </application-components>

    <project-components/>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <applicationConfigurable id="Shifter" displayName="Shifter" instance="com.kstenschke.shifter.ShifterConfigurable"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <group id="ShifterActionGroup" text="Shift Word at Caret / Line / Selection" popup="false">
            <separator/>

            <action id="ShiftUpAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftUpAction" text="Shift-Up"
                    description="Shift-Up Word at Caret / Line / Selection">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt PERIOD"/>
            </action>
            <action id="ShiftDownAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftDownAction" text="Shift-Down"
                    description="Shift-Down Word at Caret / Line / Selection">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt COMMA"/>
            </action>

            <action id="ShiftUpMoreAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftUpMoreAction" text="Shift-Up more"
                    description="Shift-Up word at care / Line / selection multiple times">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt K"/>
            </action>
            <action id="ShiftDownMoreAction" class="com.kstenschke.shifter.actions.ShiftDownMoreAction" text="Shift-Down more"
                    description="Shift-Down word at care / Line / selection multiple times">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl shift alt J"/>
            </action>

            <add-to-group group-id="EditMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </group>
    </actions>

</idea-plugin>
